Fergal O'Connor ｜ KERIA & Signify Path to Production ｜ KERI Conference 2026
My name is Fergal. I'm the
identity solutions lead architect at the
Cardano Foundation. I've been there for
the last four years building out our
open source identity solution known as
Veridian. Some of you may have seen
that this morning in Thomas'
presentation on the 5Ws.
Over a year ago, we launched the
Veridian wallet to the public app
stores. This is the first KERI/ACDC
mobile wallet in production. It's
based on KERI and Signify. We
invested a lot of time and effort into
bringing a nice user experience to
the user. You know abstracting away
the details of low-level KERI and
giving something that's actually usable
to the end user. So in doing that we
had to actually contribute a lot of
things back to KERI and Signify.
Yesterday I spoke about the security
architecture of KERI and Signify. But
today I'll talk about the path to
production. I think there are some
maturity gaps in the implementation of
KERI and Signify that should be addressed
for adoption of the KERI suite. It's
starting to lag behind the maturity of
KERIPy. We'll kind of step through
that today.
So, I mean yesterday's talk gave kind of an
in-depth explanation of how it works in
practice. But kind of the tagline
that I had was agent in the cloud
controller at the edge. So KERIA
allows you to deploy cloud agents
which essentially handle all of the
verification of KERI/ACDC/CESR up in the
cloud and allow you to use an edge
client library known as Signify at
the edge to just assign key
events essentially or ACDCs this
keeps the edge layer very thin.
For example, Veridian wallet on our mobile
just uses a Signify-ts to sign
things essentially and all of the
complex validation logic is pushed to
the cloud kind of like a black box
essentially. So in many ways it
becomes a more easy to use
API that's higher level
which is desirable for adoption
It gives something that's a bit
more tangible for people to develop on.
And very quickly, this is taken from
my deck yesterday, but doesn't look so
good on the four screens there but if
KERIA is this kind of block in the
middle is the multi- agent service it's
based on KERIPy. So it's a Python
service. It allows you to spin up
various agents in the cloud that are
fully isolated. So they have separate
databases. And for every agent in
the cloud, you have exactly one
Signify client at the edge. So this
these could be various applications from
various people sharing the same cloud
agent. This could be on a mobile
device for example. And there's a
secure communication between each client
and agent. Which I delved into
yesterday. I won't do that today.
And the agent is also responsible for
interfacing with everything else on the
network. Such as witnesses and
watchers and issuers and verifiers and
so forth. So Signify only ever talks
to the cloud agent.
– Quick question if I may. So why
must there only be one Signify client
per agent? So for example, if I
had a Veridian wallet and I had a
browser wallet. Why couldn't I both
connect to the same agent? What would be
the problem with that?
Do the Signify clients have different
key material?
– No, same password passcode.
Well, for me that's moving around the
passcode a bit too much.
Well, it's the same user though, right?
I have my phone and I have another two
phones or two devices. What's the
problem with that?
There wouldn't actually be a problem
with that if it's effectively the same
client. If you're using the same
passcode, it is effectively the same
client, just a different instance of it.
It'll derive the same key
material and authenticate in the same
way.
But if your applications keep local states
you might it might cause
inconsistencies essentially. So
– Okay. But it might work.
It would work. Yeah.
Although it might then .., how
it actually stores data on KERI needs
to be the same. You've seen this when
you've tried to connect your
wallet to what was our wallet. Yeah, it
works but you see some fuzzy stuff
that's related to our wallet only.
But yeah, this is generally the setup.
And today I've kind of split into
three different sections of what I will
cover on how we can mature KERI and
Signify. First is focused on the
developer experience. The second on
the operational resilience and third on
scalability. I think the first two
are the most important to do in the
short term. To really you know
increase the usability of the stack.
Scalability is more relevant in the long
term. A lot of people think about this
now but these first two points are more
relevant in my opinion and scalability
will be very relevant for SEDI though you
know if we're launching KERI
instances that want to serve thousands
and thousands and thousands of people
with wallets and scalability becomes a
big concern. And just to preface as
well, I mean this is going to be a talk
probably explaining all the bad points
of KERI and Signify, but it does work.
It is in production. It's just maybe
a bit nuanced to work with. It's very
unless you understand it, it can be hard
to work with because there's a lack of
feedback in places. But all of that is
really just traditional software
development points that are missing.
Just some extra maturity. It's not like
it's not anything related to the
protocols as such or the security.
And in places where I say that, oh,
and in places where I say that 'Oh,
there's not enough API hardening in
place', the reality of that is just
something happened. The KERIA crashes.
It's not a security bug. For as so much
as I can see, it's more about a
resilience thing; okay?
So, on the developer experience the
first point on this slide
refers to 'At the edge.' So everything in
Signify essentially.
We've been working quite hard over the
last at least 6 months I think to
strongly type the edge libraries so I
mean if you're using Typescript
you should be using types essentially
but when Signify was originally written
It didn't have any types in it
This is problematic if you're
refactoring code and so forth things
start to break. So we've put a lot
of time and effort to strongly type
Signify. It's not fully there yet,
but it pretty much almost is. And
instead of adding types directly into
Signify, we've actually taken a kind of
A different approach because as I
mentioned yesterday, Signify essentially
is an API wrapper around
KERIA. It can do extra things like
generate key events and sign them, but
it's otherwise an API wrapper. And
since you have an API on KERIA, you can
let KERIA decide what it wants and what
it will respond with through its open
API documentation. It will say
at this endpoint, it will give a
response in this format if it's a HTTP
200 or whatever. So,
and this is common practice, to take open
API documentation and autogenerate types
in languages. So that's what we've
done: We've updated all of the open API
docs on KERIA and generated types in
Signify-ts and Signify Java because they
propagate to various languages now as
a single source of truth and if you
wanted to add in another Signify like a
Rust library you could just
automatically generate them. Now you
might have to do some reworking in
places.
Java for example is
not as expressive in its type system as
TypeScript is. It didn't play nice
with a lot of the semantics of CESR.
But we've kind of got it working now.
So it took some changes there but
it's quite useful and also we're not
hand rolling the open API docs. We're
actually taking
the data structures in KERIPy that
Sam has written saying "Here are the
top level fields of an ACDC, we've
converted those into Python data classes
automatically generated so they can be
reused in KERIA and those data classes
are converted to the open API docs" and
you what that gives you is, if there's an
update you know downstream, it propagates
upstream and the open API docs don't go
out of sync. So this has been a huge
lift to make it more usable.
Internally, I think Signify still needs
some work.
Probably we can get away with not doing
that for a bit. There's maybe some other
points that are more relevant to that
point. I would say we'd maybe tackle
this when we're upgrading to CESR2,
which would be quite a bit of work as well.
So, quick question if I may. So
some of the WebOfTrust developers
refer to Signify meaning ..? Is it what
Signify-ts has in it? I always thought
of it as like the protocol that KERIA
exposes. So is Signify a component or is
it a protocol or is it all things or I
don't ... So how would you define what
Signify is? So sorry it's a simple
question, but it's a language question mostly.
An 'Edge client' that you can ...
– Any edge client of KERIA?
Yeah.
– Okay. Got it.
Yeah. There's a KERIA
protocol essentially,
– Right, it's defined as a protocol, but
it could be Signify JS or Signify Java
or
Yeah.
whatever other language.
How does it look like? Is it
UX stuff or is it command line stuff or
library?
Library. So when you're using Signify-ts,
it's like having
a compiler error if you type in the
wrong formats, essentially. So if you try
to create an ACDC or something, it will
know what the structure should look like
and you can reference it directly.
Whereas before you're kind of blind,
essentially.
Maybe you receive an ACDC back
from KERIA and you were going to present
that in the UI and you would say I want
to get the top level 'I' field as the
issuer.
If you were to reference some field that
doesn't exist, like 'T', before it
wouldn't complain and you just get a
blank space in the UI whereas now
TypeScript would say there is no top
level T field in an ACDC. So
I'm a strong believer in
strongly-typed languages.
The payoff is very high in terms of
keeping the bug count low and
especially when you refactor.
To your question: It's a library
you need to be able to build that you
want on top of
sort of a hole in the wall to service
food. Like you give to the other side.
The delivery desk.
Yeah,
you have the back office which is
KERIA
and then you have this (service window, red)
and then you can
deliver it out to the UX (User Interface, red)
"Serving window" or something?
Yeah.
Okay. And with this you know what's
going to come out, what shape it will
be, what comes through the serving
window whereas before it's like you're
blindfolded.
No, I'm good. Another one which is
a bit technical. Currently with in
all of the Signify implementations
When you want to do something like
issue a credential
in one command on Signify
it will construct the credential
Try to create the interaction event
to anchor it in your Key Event Log. It
will pick the sequence number for you
and submit it to the API all in one go.
Absolutely.
Which automates workflows of several
steps. Yeah.
Yeah. Which is not a good thing because
if you lose the HTTP response
you've now lost data; okay? It's okay
when you use Signify completely
stateless in smaller applications but
when you want to build enterprise
applications where you need
mission critical reliability you need
things to go through. So if you want
outbox patterns, you need to be able to
decouple those things. So you can create
and sign at the edge and then submit.
And the API should be idempotent.
Yeah.
On that particular note, I want to
make I want to hear more what you have
to say on outbox patterns. That's
actually something I was looking into.
It seems like that while we're
considering this,
we should consider the API, the
fundamental design of the API between
Signify and KERIA because one of the
reasons why we have so many different
HTTP payloads instead of just CESR
streams which if we were to just had
streams the outbox it would be very
straightforward
is because we didn't have a fully a
complete parser and cryptographic
primitives implementation in TypeScript
when Signify-ts was being first created.
And so, we ended up doing, a bit of what
you would say is, a bulkier API
from Signify-ts to KERIA because
really we should just be passing CESR
strings around. And instead we have these
and embeds that we put in HTTP messages.
And so I it's sort of a something
that I've wondered about as part of
maturing the Signify and KERIA. But
even before we even get there, I do
think we should architect everything the
way that you're saying about outboxes:
save everything locally. That makes a
lot of sense. So
but I'm just sort of saying if we're
going to do that anyway, maybe we should
reconsider what we even send per
endpoint.
Yeah, that's a big refactor as well or
change rather. Yeah,
but you could put helper functions,
you know, also in Signify-ts, sorry,
that either give the structure or raw C.
Okay, going
I'll finish because I have like 10 sides
of this. This is on our fork. We've
done this already with identifier
creation. So, we create the identifier
locally and then submit it and it allows
us to get reliability in our wallet,
which we couldn't get before. But we
probably need to apply this everywhere.
Can you say that again? You create the
identifier and then submit it. Yeah. So
the post call is decoupled. So we
can put it into an outbox locally and
push it up. We've gone to a lot of
lengths for reliability in our wallet,
but you need to do things like that for
it. And you also get better control
in the sequence number for anchoring. So
if you're trying to assign multiple
things at once, especially in a group
multi context, having better control
will be better.
– How is this how is that just
different from Signify right now? Is that
what the 10 slides are
example, right now in Signify, your IPEX
is decoupled. You create the IPEX
message and you submit it.
It's two calls. Everything else isn't,
but it should all be like IPEX.
I see.
Yeah.
Wants to go through.
Maybe I should leave the room.
All right.
Okay. It's just an example of the
TypeScript generated,
a snippet of it. It's a very long file.
And in Java there's like hundreds of
classes generated but .. This is what
we're contributing. The other
developer experience issue, and this is
actually probably even a bigger issue,
And you see this all the time on
Discord for new developers is
Silent Failures
where you submit something to
KERIA
and nothing's happening essentially.
Now with KERI when you submit things
that take time you get an operation back
and you can track the operation
completion such as if it's waiting for
witness receipts and so forth. But
it's so common to have operations that
are stuck in pending forever and you
have no idea why and you can't trace it
down and it's because you had a
different SAID in this place of this .., and
there's very little feedback to why
that happened.
– You want to put more weight on it?
Yeah, you just need more you just need
better feedback patterns essentially.
It's probably a case by case basis
to do that. This is at kind of the
API layer. It needs it needs work.
– But there could be like a 'result key' kind
of pattern applied to the call so
that if there's a failure in any call,
it's handled in a consistent way/
Yeah. But this is not the call. The call
is like it accepts it and it puts it
onto a parser
and then the result of parsing that
doesn't result in a fully signed
something because something was wrong
and you have no idea why and you're
tracing through the logs and there's a
million logs.
I don't have a I mean this is case by
case basis so you'd have to step through
the code and find the biggest issues but
even if you historically look at the
GitHub issues or Discord you'll see what
pops up most. This one
I think we fixed this one and actually
caused a different issue or
not sure.
Yeah, we made a change. Yeah, cuz it
wasn't
anyway. Yeah, but in general it just
needs work. I would say it's a
barrier to entry. Yeah, I've seen
this too often where the operation just
times out and you have no idea why.
I would think they're probably the two
biggest things you could do for the
developer experience. So, it's actually
easy to build on, you know because
if you get stuck wondering why this
isn't working for hours and hours and
hours, it's
If you finally convince someone to try KERI
Yeah.
and they start developing and this is
experience.
Yeah. But this these are easy things to
fix. It just takes a little bit time to
go through certain edge cases. The
harder one to fix is the typing which
we've almost done. So, that's the good
news. The second so that was
developer experience. The second kind
of section is Operational Resilience
you know after you deploy it
what that looks like. Some of these
might bleed back into developer
experience though. Related to the
last one is API hardening. They're
kind of overlapping. But additionally
not just
you know KERIA getting stuck in the
state where things are pending. It's
also a bit crash prone from certain bad
inputs.
What happens if it crashes?
Well, if it's in the Docker setup, it
just comes back up. That's fine. But
we even see in our
developer KERI deployment that we use
at Veridian and you'll have some random
person in the community trying to do the
previous slide sending the wrong input
and they crash our instance and all of
our wallets are flashing to offline mode
because KERIA has gone down and up,
it needs a bit more
resilience, at that point. It's not
on the parser. It's actually just on
things like the granter and things like
that. All the dexter and the agent in
file.
It's the development, not the
production.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
He says our wallets are going up and
down. That's
the development environment.
Yeah. Yeah.
They don't have access to our
production.
And, of course, KERI is multi-
agent. Okay. So yeah, like I just said,
you're now denying service to other
people just because you're submitting
the wrong thing. And it bloats the
logs with lots of errors. That could be
nice,
you know, information back to the user.
You submitted the wrong thing.
Yeah, I believe
this was the one we fixed recently.
So it doesn't crash anymore if you
point your IPEX
Admit to the wrong ..., instead of
pointing it back to the grant, you point
it to a different string. It caused a
crash. Now it causes
a an operation that's pending forever.
So you just pushed it down one layer.
Another one is application layer
reliability.
I think there's kind of a misconception
that the escrows in KERIPy are
meant to provide application layer
reliability, but they're not. They're
more they're more so to
handle out-of-order processing; okay?
In reality, if you want full reliability
at the application layer between
two wallets, their agents will need to
continuously resend information
Until they get a acknowledgements
back. For example
currently if I send an IPEX grant and my
KERI sends it to the port of another
KERI instance and it's accepted 202
all that's done is:
put it onto the parser.
It's not going to give you any
feedback if it crashes. The parser is in
memory right? So if their KERI instance
goes down at that point in time when you
just got the 202 back, you have no idea
that they didn't parse it at all.
They've never seen it essentially. So
for application reliability, we need
retries on that.
– When you're talking about “they”, you
mean the other controllers agent
maybe not even related to your agent
other than it's on the same KERIA. So,
I was experiencing the need for
retries that I didn't understand because
I have a good network. But it
could just so as a defensive programming
when you get the 202 or other certain
other areas, you need to retry. It's not
necessarily a network error.
Yeah.
Is that what you're saying? It's the
KERIA is busy or dropped it.
Yeah. I mean, so on the 3902 port, the
CESR endpoint of KERIA, it will just
take in the CESR stream and put it
onto the queue of the parser and give
you a 202 back and then parse it. But if
it gives you the 202 back and
immediately crashes, you've now lost
that data.
They have no idea that they need to
parse something. They can't parse it.
It's lost in memory. But the 3902 port
isn't used by Signify-ts, right? It's
I'm not talking about Signify-ts here.
I'm talking about entire KERI here,
but agent-to-agent communication. Yeah.
but also from Signify clients.
can use it if they want to?
3902 is open.
Yeah. But Signify-ts doesn't do anything
with it, out-of-the box, right?
No, it doesn't out-of-the box. No.
But also, if your agent accepts,
an IPEX message, it should
send it, right?
Especially for groups. So, for example,
if you have a group set up
based on KERIA and Signify
Let's say, the one person proposes an
IPX message, sends it to the others, it
starts collecting signatures. before it
collects enough signatures, it goes
down, comes back up, receives the other
signatures, nothing happens. It doesn't
send it to the other person. Because the
granter deck is in memory, the queue.
So, it's lost it. And the lead of the
group currently is the one that sends.
So, a lot of the in-memory decks that we
use for cues in KERI need to be made
durable. So
Is there an issue? If there's not an
issue with that, I'm going to make that
one right now. That's
Yeah, that's bad. That one
that one's bad, actually. That needs to
be fixed soon. But you don't see
these in your normal setups like
because it's just "happy paths,"
everything just works. Everyone clicks
at the same time.
It's all good.
Yeah.
And it'd be nice to have some more
feedback on the async stuff because
everything in KERI is async. So,
if we have better ways of receiving
results that are more rich on what's
happening, that would be useful. But
that's a bit open-ended.
I mean, if you already have a plan to
put these into issues, I don't want to
duplicate it. But is there
a plan to currently make an
(GitHub, red) Issue on that because if there's not,
I'll capture it immediately.
I have a joint (GitHub, red) Discussion but I don't
know if it has everything from this. It
was written a while ago. It's either
in Signify-ts or KERIA (GitHub repos, red).
that's some information from Sam on
application layer reliability.
If you want to read it, it's him saying
that KERIPy is not going to provide
this essentially.
What is him saying again?
About achieving application layer
reliability end to end.
Okay, cool. And the need for retries and
idempotency, so forth.
Cool.
Finally, well, not finally.
Especially when you're using group
multisig, and if you're doing something
wrong, it can be quite hard to
understand what you're doing wrong
because it's a multi-agent setup. All
your logs are intertwined. There's no
way to filter on the logs. And even if
there was a way to filter on the logs
per agent, there's still too many
logs, there's no way to filter on the
action you were trying to do. And
data again, everything's based on HIO.
Everything's async, everything's moving
various ways with little
observability. It's again fine,
once you've developed it's fine,
but sometimes it can be very
difficult to add new features to KERIA
and try and figure out where the data is
actually moving and what's actually
wrong and why it isn't completing and
so forth.
Should the KERIA requests have a
request ID added to them?
Probably. Yeah. But it'll need
some work with KERIPy as well
because most of the complex logic of
KERIA is KERIpy. It's a direct
dependency. It gets pushed onto KERIPy.
So I need to do some work
there. So yeah, some instrumentation
would be useful at that.
You see you go through the
logs and you're just trying to figure
out what's going on, because you've put
the wrong ID somewhere, and it's ...,
You can see Kent added some
stuff here. But we probably need
to go a bit further so we can actually
filter on IDs of agents and so forth.
A structured log.
Yeah.
Request ID or client ID.
I'll do this one quite quickly.
Yeah, probably KERI and Signify should
have some semantic versioning because
it's an API. And I think you raised
issues on this. There should be
compatibility enforcements between them.
I don't think this is big issue now,
but in as you move towards
being a more mature ecosystem and
getting more developers in, it'll become
more relevant. Also versioning.
Right now you have to version on the
KLI per agent and iterate over them. So
there needs to be a migration framework
in place. We've been avoiding this
for ages because there hasn't been
migrations, essentially, but when there is
in production it would be
problematic. So that's resilience.
And again these are
traditional software problems
Just put some resources in
and it'll make it a more mature app
It's not a protocol thing. These are
all very achievable.
Finally on Scalability
And this one is also a kind of
developer experience
I mentioned earlier that because a lot
of the things are async, you need to
submit like create an identifier, create
a registry, issue a credential and you
get an operation back.
And then you need to pull on that
status of the operation until it's done
while it's waiting to collect signatures
and so forth. That's kind of a pain.
Typical modern systems are usually
event driven. Where you would get
some notification that it has completed
rather than constantly checking.
The same goes for notifications. You
have to constantly check if there's new
new notifications.
You know in any general application like
a wallet, it's going to have to
constantly check because it doesn't know
when to expect that you're receiving a
credential.
– Single-threaded environment, it could
completely
block the rest of the application.
Yeah.
We've made event driven in our
wallet in every application we've built
because we've just put it in a corner in
the box and made it event driven from
the perspective of the rest of our
application. But it's kind of annoying
to have to build that every single time.
But this is very doable, if we were to
take the query reply
approach of just using the
the WSGI response stream, we could open
up the server ... connection per
agent. Yep.
To Signify and do this today.
I might try that over the weekend.
Huh?
No.
Tell me about it.
Before I get to that.
The reason I put this in scalability is
because right now you have 10,000
wallets using one KERI nstance and
they have 25 pending operations that
they're pulling, pulling, pulling. These
are all full HTTP requests. It's way too
much traffic hitting KERIA.
It won't work. So moving to something
like Server Sent Events
is much better from a developer
experience, but it's also much better
from a load experience. And
it isn't, ..., I've never
implemented them, so I don't know what
it's like, but for notifications, it
wouldn't be too difficult because it's
just the next notification coming out on
the event. It's more problematic for
operations. I explain that in a moment.
I also Server Sent Events are true
HTTP, so they're compatible with load
balancers. So if you start to do
horizontal scaling and so forth, they're
compatible, which is why Sam
would prefer that over
websockets because that isn't pure HTTP.
Now the problem for integrating
with operations is currently
when you perform an action that requires
a long run operation to track that
state of the operation.
It just stores the related SAIDs and
metadata that refer to that operation.
It doesn't have a status of pending or
failed or anything like that.
And when you use Signify to check that
status of pending or failed, it's not
stored in the database. That's what I
mean. It doesn't flip in the database
from pending to complete
actually if you look at longridden.py
in KERI, it takes all of those SAIDs
and compares it against the database of
the agent to see if it's effectively
complete. Okay, so it's not checking is
this operation complete in the database.
check in based on this operations
metadata are all the signatures in place
for this to be considered complete for
example you can see here for the
delegations using the 'swain.complete'
every time you check
Yeah, basically like a diff on the
database
– Yeah, this has been quite a mental
challenge for me for like two years with
KERI is the notion that the concept of
state and state modeling is missing
and that's intentional
I think from Sam
IPEX for example, right, is ..
I tried to get a state
machine diagram of all the possible
state transitions and IPEX of Spurn,
Grant, Accept, and all that and
I had a challenge getting to the
precision but this is similar: You're
wanting to query the state of an
operation and it has to be derived and
has to be requeried to compute the state.
That is what I think I heard you say.
Yeah.
...of an operation, right? So it'd be
nice just to get the state back
from KERIA like 'Oh, it's in Pending'.
Yeah. So basically while currently
we can't do event driven with
Server Sent Events.
To date?
Because it's you're checking against the
database state. Okay. So instead of
checking the database state or the diff
when this completes for the first time
inside KERIPy, it needs to emit an
event that gets sent on server the
Server Sent Event
thread.
Okay. Because I'm thinking what we could
do for each operation type is that there
could be there's already a
server event connection from the agent
to the Signify client. It would
essentially just be a channel to
communicate. I'm thinking on completion
it would just send a completion.
Yeah. But there is no completion of an
operation in KERIA. It's a state check.
It tells you it's effectively complete.
There's no point where it's in the
database ..,
– Iit's inferred
Yeah, it's inferred. So if you
never ever connect it again,
nothing changes on the database to say
it's complete. It's just you coming back
later and saying this is the status.
Okay. So because there's no point at
which that happens
This is a problem all the
time, right?
So essentially
we need to store the completed state, not
just derive it.
Yeah, All of this happens
in KERIPy so KERIPy needs to tell us
because this is a KERIA thing
operations aren't in KERIPy
– .. locally in KERIA per agent so because
once we derive it once even though we're
reading it
yeah but what triggers to derive it
other than you're going to move the
polling inside internally
– What triggers what?
What triggers 'Check and it's complete.'
in KERIA.
So this is where I think what we should
do when we have an operation
There should be a Doer for each
operation
once it completes at the end before that
Doer finishes it should write the
complete state.
Yeah. But now you've just
moved all of the polling internal to KERIA
and you'd have so many doers for 10,000
Signified clients. So it would
be a lot better if internally in KERIPy
It could just let us know when it's
effectively completed
because there's already something inside
KERIPy tracking this I would say. So
then it can admit that event or whatever
and we can capture it and update our
operation in the database and send the
event back and Server Sent Events.
Yeah, I think we're slightly talking
past each other but I think I get what
you're saying. I think fundamentally
when an important event happens in KERIPy,
it should be admitted saying "this and this
happened."
Yeah.
Rather than having new Doers that are
also tracking it again.
Cool, just one more slide. So it's
actually good.
No, actually one; so not too bad.
Yeah, and horizontal scaling.
People have asked about this before
I would put this on the lowest priority.
because other things just need to be
fixed first to get adoption. But for
SEDI it would be important.
Okay, right now you could do something
like sticky sessions. It would be a very
naive approach. Where you
deploy 10 different KERIAs and you
have a load balancer and once a
client connects and gets routed to a
KERIA instance they always have to go
there, forever. That's like a sticky
session. It would work now, but it
wouldn't be great.
To do true horizontal scale, I think KERI is
actually already quite suited to it.
Because all the databases of agents are
fully isolated and no agents are shared.
They're just a bunch of LMDB files.
So if you had to ... [reformulates, red.]
The easiest thing you could do is have a
shared volume in your cloud deployment
that all of the instances can access and
they would just go to the specific LMDB
files that they're currently
serving. And if it's done correctly
they won't try to access the same LMDB
file of someone else and you could have
the agency coordinate that. If you
wanted more isolation, I guess you could
separate the volumes, but I think that
would be
a little bit complex, not necessary.
You'd be moving data across
volumes. I don't like that for now.
At least I don't think it's necessary.
Unless there's a
legal constraint on data or something.
And yeah, the agency can become the
load balancer, like it currently is
basically for the message router in
KERIA. But instead it would
actually be outside
KERIA and route into a more
light-weight KERIA. So you kind of
decouple it a bit; be different services.
I think that's more down the line.
So that's why developer experience
and operational resilience are highest
priority, I think. Yeah, Done!
– What's this up there?
That's the file system.
The agency database is an LMDB
database. You can see that there was two
new agents booted. There are the config
files that get copied in the JSON config
files with the OOBIs.
And for each
agent they have a subdirectory in all
of these directories. Like there's the
key store, for example.
Probably it would be better if you
restructure it, so that the agent is at
the top level and it has its databases
internally so you can more easily take
it. But if it was a shared volume
across many instances it wouldn't
matter.